

Kenny McGeoch

WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Kenny is a self-taught frontend web developer, with two years of experience across React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Node. In additional to several personal development projects, he has collaborated with a local developer on the local Badgers Brook club website.

In his spare time, Kenny is a highly rated competitive chess player in multiple Scottish chess leagues. He has been treasurer for the Central Scotland Chess League for over a decade and is an active member of the Standards Committee of Chess Scotland. His financial interest also extends to the investment world, where he manages several personal portfolios.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Location

Livingston, Scotland

CONTACT

K.McGeoch@gmail.com

07493 646677 or 01560 429890

WORK EXPERIENCE

Javascript Developer

SMARTBRAIN 2022-2023

Face recognition website using Clarifai API to identify faces submitted. Website is built with React and user details are kept in a SQL database. User registration is enabled and password is stored as a hash with all confidential data stored on the back end.

Technologies Used: React, Node, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, PostgresSQL, Clarifai, JSON tsparticles, Tachyons, Tilt-parallax, bcrypt-nodejs, knex, express Live:https://kennymcgeoch.github.io/smartbrain/

Javascript Developer

POKEDEX 2021 to 2023

This project access data from the PokeAPI RESTful API. It then uses array/object manipulation to access the information displayed in the cards. It is quite easy to add extra information but I thought it's name, pokedex entry, types and picture gives a nice illustration as proof of concept. It also contains a search function so you can look up an individual pokemon.

Technologies Used: React, Node, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, RESTful API Live: https://kennymcgeoch.github.io/Pokedex/

Javascript Developer

SUDOKU 2022 to 2023

This program solves sudoku puzzles using textboxes as inputs. All non single digit inputs are discarded when it's passed to the solver in the form of a nested array. If the starting position is invalid or there are no possible solutions it will diplay an appropriate error message. Otherwise it solves the sudoku with a valid potentially non-unique solution and displays a confetti animation upon success. As a quality of life improvement I added an option to reset the board.

Technologies Used: React, Node, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, canvas-confetti Live: https://kennymcgeoch.github.io/Sudoku/

Javascript Developer

ROBOFRIENDS 2021 to 2023

This generates Robot images using the Robohash API that generates a Robot based on text input. The random names are acquired via a fetch request to https://jsonplaceholder.typicode.com/users. Then it's displayed as a card with a search feature added. While functionally the same there are 3 versions coded with changes so that it uses React Hooks and Redux that changes the implementation but the user experience is unchanged.

Technologies Used: React, Node, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, RESTful API, Redux, Hooks Live: https://kennymcgeoch.github.io/RoboFriends/

Document Service Operator

CANON 2015 to 2021

Worked on inbound and outbound document services for Aegon, Hertz and Gloucester City Council. I also provided improvements to the work processes that allowed for increased amounts of automation allowing us to deliver cost savings to the client.

Operator

WILLIAMS LEA 2011 to 2014

Used bespoke software as part of a team handling of insurance claims for RSA. During my time working on the contract it was extended for a further 7 years as the client was very happy with our work.

EDUCATION

Bsc Chemistry (hons)

EDINBURGH UNIVERSITY

2002-2006

SKILLS

Javascript ES6 CSS3 HTML5 React Node JS Github PostgresSQL